JACK MUMFORD

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research focuses on the challenge of advancing explainable AI systems that can provide rationales for their outputs. I am interested in building machine learning that is logically coherent and investigating the extent to which such learning can accommodate effective human-computer interaction in order to engender greater trust in the output. In particular I examine the intersection of neural networks (subsymbolic) and argumentation semantics (symbolic), resulting in neural argumentation networks (NANs) that learn in a logically coherent manner according to argumentation principles.

EDUCATION

2016 - 2017 MSc in Intelligent Systems

King's College London, Department of Informatics, UK

Distinction

2012 - 2016 BSc in Mathematics

The Open University, School of Mathematics and Statistics, UK

1st Class (Honours)

RESEARCH

2017 - PhD candidate in Computer Science

King's College London, Department of Informatics, UK

Thesis: Exploring the connections between argumentation and neural networks in producing data-driven decision making.

Supervisors: Professor Simon Parsons (School of Computer Science, University of Lincoln), Dr Elizabeth Black (Department of Informatics, King's College London) and Dr Isabel Sassoon (Department of Computer Science, Brunel University London).

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

2017 - Graduate Teaching Assistant

King's College London, Department of Informatics, UK

Taught small and large tutorial groups as well as computer lab practical sessions for undergraduate and masters level modules:

• Machine Learning • Data Mining • Software Measurement & Testing • Introduction to Robotics • Simulation & Data Visualisation.

Additional duties: coursework marking; moderation, invigilation and second marking of examinations.

2014 - 2016 GCSE and A-Level Mathematics Tutor

West Midlands, UK

Self-employed in providing private one-one tuition for secondary school students studying for examination at GCSE and A-Level mathematics. Developed tailored lesson plans, marked homework, provided learning goals and provided relevant feedback in order to develop the students' confidence in the subject and their own abilities.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2012 - 2014

Programme Co-ordinator/Operations Co-ordinator

University of Warwick, Warwick Business School, UK

I had responsibility for the successful administrative delivery of undergraduate modules (as Programme Co-ordinator) and distance learning masters-level content (later as Operations Co-ordinator). Both roles involved:

• Carefully monitoring student enquiries and providing timely responses by email, telephone and face-to-face • Supporting preparation and running of departmental open days • Analysing core statistics with Excel, Access and Outlook; and producing reports based upon departmental performance data.

The role of Operations Co-ordinator also required production of invoices for necessary materials. The role of Programme Co-ordinator also involved meeting with prospective students and their parents to explain and advocate the courses offered by the department.

2010 - 2012

Customer Services Officer

HSBC Bank, Stratford-upon-Avon, UK

The role entailed driving the quantity of sales and the quality of service within a challenging target assessed team environment. Additionally I was accepted onto the internal fast track Promotion Scheme (Talent Pool). My duties included:

• Facilitating transactions from International Payments to more complex matters such as Personal Lending • Securing appointments and providing financial service via telephone • Auditing work and organisating branch procedural checks (following my promotion to act an authorised Signatory of the bank) • Flexibly supporting smaller branches of the bank, in various locations, in a supervisory role as and when required.

AWARDS & GRANTS

 \blacksquare 2019

Nominated for King's Education Award (King's College London)

2019

Outstanding Teaching Assistant Award (Dept. of Informatics, King's College London)

2017 - 2020

PhD studentship (EPSRC)

2017

Prize for the best overall performance on the MSc in Intelligent Systems (Dept. of Informatics, King's College London)

ACADEMIC SERVICE

⊞ 2020 -

Department of Informatics TA Liaison Committee (King's College London)

TA Representative

2019 -

Online Handbook for Argumentation in Artificial Intelligence (OHAAI)

Co-Founder & Editor

2019 -

Argumentation Reading Group (King's College London)

Co-Founder & Member

2016 - 2017

Department of Informatics Postgraduate Staff Student Liaison Committee (King's College London)

Student Representative & Co-chair (from 2017)

OTHER SKILLS

Programming	knowledge
Languages	

Python, MATLAB, Java, HTML, LaTeX.

English (fluent), French (intermediate), Spanish (intermediate).

SCIENTIFIC TALKS



• Building Neural Argumentation Networks (NANs) - automating the learning of attack relationships from data. Seminar for the Reasoning and Planning Group, Department of Informatics, King's College London, UK.



- Building Neural Argumentation Networks (NANs) automating the learning of attack relationships from data. Presentation at the Argumentation Workshop, Imperial College London, UK.
- Argumentation Machine Learning. Seminar for the Argumentation Reading Group, King's College London, UK.
- Attack learning using a feed-forward neural network. Seminar for the Argumentation Reading Group, King's College London, UK.
- Calculating Dung semantics attack-relations using a feed-forward neural network. Presentation at the London Argumentation Forum, Imperial College London, UK.

PUBLICATIONS

Published papers:

1. J. Mumford (2020). "Crafting neural argumentation networks". Online Handbook of Argumentation for AI: Volume 1. arXiv:2006.12020 [cs.AI].

Papers being prepared for submission:

- 2. J. Mumford, I. Sassoon, E. Black and S. Parsons. "Deriving argumentation framework attack-relations from data using a feed-forward neural network". Being prepared for submission to *Artificial Intelligence*, expected submission date July 2020.
- 3. J. Mumford, I. Sassoon, E. Black and S. Parsons. "On the complexity of mapping attacks to argument acceptability data". Being prepared for submission to *Thirty-Fifth AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence*, expected submission date September 2020.

Edited books:

4. Online Handbook of Argumentation for AI: Volume 1 (2020). arXiv:2006.12020 [cs.AI].